太空堡垒卡拉狄加 【 前情提要 】
TIGH: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
赛昂人组建了一支人类警察部队
ROSLIN: The Cylons have established a human police force.
我们的几百名同胞被赛昂人集中在一起
Hundreds of us have been rounded up by the Cylons,
关押 审问 蹂躏
held in detention, questioned, tortured.
这是什么?
What's this?
这是一份对所有犯人的处决书
This orders the summary executions
他们的名字都在下一页
of all the detainees listed on the next page.
需要你的签名
It requires your signature.
签字!  签上你的名字!
Sign it! Sign your name!
赛昂人对我们的动向了如指掌
The Cylons knew exactly where we were gonna be.
听我解释
I want to explain.
她出卖了我们
SAM: She sold us out.
你知道该怎么做了吧
You know what has to be done here.
为了她好  还是由你来亲自动手
Now, it would be better for her sake if it was you.
你不怕代表这个十恶不赦的人出庭?
You're not afraid to represent the most hated man alive?
我想见一下我的委托人
I'd like to see my client.
如果他们要害我  他们自有办法
If they want to kill me, they'll find a way.
不!
No!
波塔尔的律师这一受伤  他的辩方会需要人手
With Baltar's lawyer injured, his defense will need help.
爸  我为什么不行?  我了解这个案子 看过相关文件
Dad, why not me? I'm close to the case, I've read the documents.
你是空军队长 不是律师
You're a CAG, you're not a lawyer.
我不会让你坐在法庭的另一端
I will not allow you to sit across the courtroom
来为波塔尔辩护
on the other side, defending Gaius Baltar.
这是命令吗?
Is that an order?
我不会再对你下命令了
I'm through giving you orders.
赫拉?
Hera?
赫拉!
Hera!
绿叶号的超光速引擎终于修好了  长官
We finally got Greenleaf's FTL nailed down, sir.
舰队又可以起程了
So, fleet's ready to jump again.
还有多少次跳跃我们才能找到那座星云?
How many more before we find the nebula?
我估计十二次 快了
I'm estimating an even dozen. We're getting close.
还是不见赛昂人的踪影?
Still no sign of the Cylons?
是的  长官  在每个跳跃点 我们都留下了一架断后机
No, sir. We've left a trailing bird in every jump site.
未发现目标 没有目击  什么都没有
No dradis contacts, no sighting, nothing.
更改断后猛禽机的命令
Alter the mission orders of the trailing Raptor.
告诉他们在返回舰队之前
Tell them to remain an additional six hours
再留守六小时
before catching up with the fleet.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
好
Yeah!
到你了  大明星
You're up, superstar!
你们知道这场比赛可他妈是动真格的吧?
You know this game's got frak-all to do with the real thing, right?
你们这群菜鸟在开始的时候可没那么说
SKULLS: Yeah. I didn't hear you nuggets say that at the beginning.
我可不管别人…
I don't really care what anybody...
好  往回调一下 就差一点
There, go back, you almost had it.
什么差一点?
SEELIX: Had what?
那首歌  你没听到么?
That song. You don't hear that song?
没有啊  来吧  到你了 走啦
No. Come on, you're up, let's go.
好吧  好吧
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
波塔尔曾协助赛昂人袭击殖民地
Baltar was instrumental in the Cylon attack on the Colonies.
总统要以种族灭绝的罪名控告他
The President wants him charged with genocide.
这我可无法认同 并没有证据显示他参与了…
I can't make it stick. There is no evidence of his involvement...
总统曾见过他与卡布里卡上的一名六号在一起
The President saw him with one of the Sixes on Caprica,
在那次袭击之前
before the attacks.
你真想把劳拉・罗丝琳推上证人席
You really want me to put Laura Roslin
来为她的药源性幻觉申辩吗?
on the stand to testify about her drug-induced visions?
我们只想让你做好本职工作 判处他有罪
What we want is for you to do your job and convict him.
如果你做不到 我们可以找其他人
You can't do that, we'll find someone who will.
我们这是以礼相见 可不是战术讨论会
This a courtesy meeting, not a strategy session.
我会秉公办事
I am charging Baltar with what I can prove.
当然 我也会讨总统的欢心
Of course, I do serve at the pleasure of the President
还有如果她决定找人替代我
and if she decides to replace me,
我确信其他律师也都愿意接手这个案子
I'm sure there are other lawyers willing to take up the case.
如果还有律师的话
If there are any other lawyers.
波塔尔博士?
Doctor Baltar?
你是哪位?
Who are you?
哦
Oh.
很抱歉 我的律师一再强调
Look, I'm terribly sorry, I'm under strict instructions from my attorney
不要与任何媒体说话
not to speak to any members of the press.
不  波塔尔博士  我…
No, Doctor Baltar, I...
我想请您看一下这张照片
I want you to look at this picture.
这是我的儿子
This is my son.
他病了 我想请您保佑他
He's sick and I want you to bless him.
保佑他?
Bless him?
守卫!
Guard!
求你了      很抱歉  我帮不了你
Please! I'm terribly sorry, but I can't help you.
我不是神仙 或是什么神灵
I'm not God, the God or a god of any derivation thereof.
求求您        我保佑不了他 对不起
Please, I... I can't bless him, I'm sorry.
我又并没什么特异功能     我信您
I don't have any special powers. I believe in you.
不敢当      这地方是怎么了?
That's very flattering. What the hell's going on here?
都成动物园了
This place is becoming like a zoo.
我在受审中 我想单独呆会
I'm on trial for my life, I need a bit of privacy.
为他祈祷吧 求你了
Just pray for him, please.
求求您               该走了
Please. GUARD: Time to go.
我尽力而为    您可以救他
I'll do my best. You can save him.
还是留意点你自己吧
Yeah, mind how you go, now.
几个了?
How many is that now?
五个
Five.
还不算30  40个写了信的人
Not including the 30 or 40 who've written letters.
这是免不了的事
Well, I suppose it can't be helped.
名人受审经常能把疯子引来
Celebrity trials invariably bring out the crazies.
你认为他们都疯了?
So you think they're crazy?
我看到的是一个痛苦的女人
You see, I saw a woman in pain.
我看到的是一个比你还要了解你自己的女人
I saw a woman who can see you more clearly than you can see yourself.
即使他们杀了你 你的名字也会名垂千史
Even if they kill you, your name will live on forever.
卡拉狄加  我是猛禽289号机
RACETRACK: Galactica, Raptor 289.
我们已就位 准备展开断后任务
We're clear and in position for rear guard picket.
收到  289号  老实呆着 替我们把风
SKULLS: Roger, two-eight-niner. Have fun watching our ass, Racetrack.
老实看着波塔尔受审
Have fun watching Baltar's ass get nailed.
好  坐稳了  12小时倒计时
All right, get comfortable. 12 hours and counting.
我们像是钓钩上的诱饵
Twelve hours hanging out here like bait on a hook,
要在这里等上12小时 查探赛昂人是否还在追踪咱们
waiting to see if the Cylons are still following us.
少说两句  发牌吧
Just shut up and deal, okay?
我们如何评估损失?
How do we measure loss?
如何评估损失?
我们以死者的面孔来评估它
We measure it in the faces of the dead,
那些萦绕于我们记忆之中与梦境之中的面孔
the faces that haunt our memories and our dreams.
我们如何评估损失?
How do we measure loss?
我们以自己的面孔来评估它
We measure it in our own faces,
我们每天都能在镜中看到的面孔
the ones we see in the mirror every day
因为它是我们每个人的标记
because it has marked each of us.
那我们如何评估损失?
So, how do we measure loss
当采用其他方法
when the scale of it becomes
已经无法衡量它的时候
too hard to absorb any other way?
我们使用数字
We use numbers.
多少人遇害 多少人受伤
How many killed? How many maimed?
多少人失踪
How many missing?
而当那些数字如同两年前一样
And when those numbers become too vast to comprehend,
过于庞大不便理解的时候
as they did two years ago,
我们只好反其道而行之
we had to turn it around.
我们开始计算活人的数目
We began to count the living,
我们之中那些幸存下来...
those of us who survived
继续谱写人类传奇的人
to continue the saga of the human race.
44035人
44,035.
曾定居在新卡布里卡上的...
The sum total of survivors from the Twelve Colonies
将盖尤斯・波塔尔总统奉为领袖与保护者的
who settled on New Caprica with President Gaius Baltar
12殖民地的幸存者数目
as their leader and protector.
是38838人
38,838.
这我们脱离苦海那一天的人数
Our number the day after we escaped.
而缺失的数目呢 在座各位都不愿面对的数字
And the missing number, the one that no one wants to face.
是5179人
5,197.
我们中的5197名同胞
5,197 of us
遇害 掉队 或是就此消失
killed, left behind or simply disappeared.
所有剩余人类中的
5,197
5197人...
of all that remains of the human race,
不见了
lost!
12殖民地的民众把他们的命运...
The citizens of the Twelve Colonies
与性命寄托在盖尤斯・波塔尔身上
entrusted their fate and their lives to Gaius Baltar.
而我们所得到的回报
What we received was a reign
却是令我们心灰意冷的恐怖统治
of terror that staggers our mind and breaks our hearts.
我们得到的不是统治 而是专制
Instead of governance, we got tyranny.
不是公正  而是压迫
Instead of justice, we got oppression.
不是总统  而是凶手
Instead of a president, we got a murderer.
今天 人类将让他承担他的罪责
Today, humanity holds him accountable for his crime.
盖尤斯・波塔尔不是受害者
Gaius Baltar is not a victim.
盖尤斯・波塔尔选择与赛昂人为伍
Gaius Baltar chose to side with the Cylons
主动迫害他的子民
and to actively seek the deaths of his fellow citizens.
就此而言...
For that...
他必须为此付出最终代价
He must pay the ultimate price.
法官大人 辩方请求被判为有罪
Your Honors, the defense would like to change our plea to guilty.
什么?
What?
律师  你确定要这么做吗?
Counselor, are you sure you want to do that?
不 可我有选择的余地么?
No, but what choice do I have?
我的委托人显然有罪
I mean, it's obvious my client is guilty.
他是个叛徒 是个杀人犯
He's a traitor and a killer.
他与赛昂人是一丘之貉 我们该怎么处置他?
He's no better than the Cylon, and what do we do with them?
把他扔出过渡舱!      对!
MAN: Throw them out the airlock! That's right!
把他扔出过渡舱!
Throw them out the airlock!
这小子把我们出卖给了敌人
This man sold us to our enemy.
这小子就是我们的敌人
This man is our enemy.
如果战争有一个好处 有一件事是正确 正当  正义的
And if there's one thing that's good in war, that is right and just and proper,
就是屠杀我们的敌人!
it's slaughtering our enemy!
报仇血恨!
Getting some righteous payback!
我们还等什么?!
What are we waiting for?
我们现在就杀了他!
Let's just kill him now!
这样不就省事多了么?
It'd be easier, wouldn't it?
简单多了
Simpler.
冤冤相报
Justice of the mob.
他们就想这样
It's what they want.
尤其是她
Especially her.
她等这一天已经一年有余
She's been wanting this for over a year now.
自从他在那场自由 公平的选举中挫败她那一刻开始
Ever since he beat her in a free and fair election of the people.
现在她终于有了一雪前耻的机会
Now she gets a chance to exact her revenge
而这个人的唯一罪行  仅仅是听天由命
upon a man whose only real crime is bowing to the inevitable.
盖尤斯・波塔尔 挽救了新卡布里卡上民众的生命
Gaius Baltar saved the lives of the people on New Caprica,
而劳拉・罗丝琳会把我们都害死
where Laura Roslin would have seen us all dead,
作为一场战争的受害者 我们没有赢的希望
victims of a battle we had no hope in winning.
我不知道诸位做何感想?
I don't know about you,
但当赛昂人从天而降说道缴枪不杀的时候
but I'm glad she wasn't the president when the Cylons arrived and said,
我很庆幸她不是总统
"Surrender or die. "
盖尤斯・波塔尔和他那天所做的决定救我一命
I owe my life to Gaius Baltar and the decision he made that day.
也包括劳拉・罗丝琳
So does Laura Roslin.
得了吧  好象你真知道似的
Yeah, like you frakking know.
我知道你在自己床上打手枪
I know you wank it in your rack.
帅哥
Ladies' man...
这叫自我疗法
You see, that's called self-healing.
好  检查时间
Okay, time check.
有情况
Oh, we got something.
好多敌人
Lots of company.
探测到三  四  五艘母舰  糟糕 他们就在我们的正上方
Reading three, four, no, five Baseships. Crap! They're right on top of us.
干 干 炮火来袭
Frak. Frak! Incoming!
超光速引擎仍在加速
The FTL's still spinning up.
我们得跳跃了
We've got to jump.
天杀的!  立即跳跃!
Now, Gods damn it. Now!
开始在整个舰队里搜索跟踪装置
Begin searching the entire fleet for tracking devices.
可能在新卡布里卡上的时候 它们就已被安置好了
It's possible they could have placed one on a ship on New Caprica.
我认为我们应该去问一下六号 她也许愿意提供帮助
I think that we should ask the Six. She may be willing to help.
波塔尔的女友 她为什么要那么做?
Baltar's girlfriend? Why would she do that?
因为她不想看到 赫拉落到赛昂人手中
Because she doesn't want to see Hera go back to the Cylons.
你认为那东西会为一个半赛昂人的崽子甘愿冒险?
You think that thing would stick her neck out for some half-Cylon whelp?
我有一种感觉  她愿以生命为代价
I have a feeling she'd lay her life down for it.
一种感觉?
A feeling?
不只是感觉  行了吧?    为什么…  就这么做吧
It's more than a feeling, all right? Why... Just do it.
问一下又有何妨
It doesn't hurt to ask.
对
No.
问一下犯人 她是否知道舰队里有任何跟踪装置
Ask the prisoner if it knows of any tracking devices in the fleet.
荣幸至致
With pleasure.
总统大人 老天保佑她活泼乐观的灵魂
The President, Gods bless her sunny optimistic soul,
认为你或许愿意透漏你的兄弟姐妹是如何跟踪我们的
thinks you might want to share how your buddies have been tracking us.
所以我来这里提出问题  听你说谎
So I'm here to ask the question and listen to your lies.
在上一次战斗中 我们发现了你们的燃料船…
In the last battle, we discovered your fuel ship
具有独特的辐射信号
had a unique radiation signature.
他们必定是找到了跟踪它的方法
They must have found a way to track it.
你还知道些什么?
What else do you know?
你那机器脑袋里还蕴藏着什么秘密?
What other secrets are rattling around inside that mechanical brain?
别怕他
Don't be intimidated by him.
他只是利用你来驱除他自身的苦痛
He's just using you to exorcise his own pain.
可怜的家伙
Poor old sod.
他失去了一个亲人
He lost someone close to him.
你了解这种感受  不是么?
But you know how that feels, don't you?
我知道很多事 有一件事你想知道么?
I know a lot of things. You want to know one thing I know?
我知道你的损失
I know about your loss.
心疼  是吧?
It hurts, doesn't it?
你都不知道自己是怎么坚持过来的
You wonder how you can even survive it.
我不明白你居心何在
I don't know what you're talking about,
可这没有用
but it's not gonna work.
她是他的全部
BALTAR: She was his world.
当然  到失去她之后他才知道
Of course, he only realized when she was gone.
她知道么?
Did she know?
她知道她对你有多重要么?
Did she know how much she meant to you?
还是直到她走了  你也没说出口?
Or did you wait to tell her till she was gone?
什么?
What?
你却让她以为自己是个累赘
Bet you made her think that she was a burden,
一个束缚你的枷锁
a millstone around your neck.
你们人类总是去毁灭爱你们的人 不是吗
But then you humans always destroy the ones who love you, don't you?
把这东西铐起来
Shackle this thing.
泰上校
CASSIDY: Colonel Tigh.
Colonel Tigh.
抱歉 是什么问题来着?
Excuse me. What was the question again?
作为起义军领袖
As the leader of the insurgency, did you ever hear of an instance
你是否听说过波塔尔反抗赛昂人
in which Baltar stood up to the Cylons
或试图破坏他们的计划?      没  从没听过
or tried to disrupt their plans? Oh, no, never.
他从没出手帮助过我们
He never lifted a frakking finger to help us.
艾伦比他强
Ellen did more.
至少她在帮我们
At least she was trying to help us.
我的天  他喝多了
Oh, my Gods, he's drunk.
对
Yes.
对  艾伦  你的夫人
Yes, Ellen, your wife.
波塔尔赛昂同盟的又一位受害者
Another victim of Baltar's Cylon allies.
对  不错
Yeah, that's right.
谢谢  上校
Thank you, Colonel.
该你来讯问证人了
Your witness.
上校的太太出了什么事?
What happened to the Colonel's wife?
她曾为一个赛昂管理员工作
She used to work for one of the Cylon administrators.
为他们卖命?
She worked for him?
你知道她出了什么事吗?
You know what happened to her?
不  不知道   我猜她在逃离新卡布里卡的时候死了
No, no idea. I presume she died in the exodus from New Caprica.
呃
Uh...
上校
Colonel.
你不喜欢盖尤斯・波塔尔
You dislike Gaius Baltar
是因为你认为他是个叛徒  对吗?
because you consider him to be a traitor. Is that correct?
还是个孬种  大屠杀的罪魁祸首
And a coward and a mass murderer.
警卫毕业典礼上的自杀式炸弹袭击
The suicide bombing of the police graduation.
盖尤斯・波塔尔才是预期目标  对吧?
Gaius Baltar was the intended target, was he not?
如果他那天有胆量到场
And if he'd had the guts to show up that day like he was supposed to,
你我现在说这些话都是多余
you and I wouldn't be having this conversation right now.
所以只为了有除掉
So you ordered the killing of...
盖尤斯・波塔尔的机会
What was it, 33 other men and women?
你就下令杀死其他33人
Just for the chance to kill Gaius Baltar.
他们都是叛徒
They were all traitors.
只要是穿上那身制服的人
Anyone who put on that uniform.
不过是的 目标是他
But, yes, he was the target.
你的夫人出了什么事?
What happened to your wife?
反对 与本案有关系么?
Exception. Relevance?
我只是就势而上 法官大人
The door was opened on direct, Your Honor.
我看不出追问此事…
I fail to see the point of pursuing the subject.
他说得对  上将
He's right, Admiral.
如果已经在初步讯问提到过
If it was brought up during direct examination,
他就可以继续追问
then it can be pursued in the cross.
反对无效  继续
Overruled. Continue.
你的夫人出了什么事  上校?
What happened to your wife, Colonel?
你他娘的狗杂种…
You frakking son of a bitch...
她与赛昂人公开勾结是真的吗?
Isn't it true that she collaborated openly with the Cylons?
确切地说  是为他们卖命?
That she actually worked for them?
她假装的
She was faking it.
使他们以为  她在为他们工作
Making them think that she was working for them.
我明白了 波塔尔可没有在伪装
I see, yeah. And Baltar, he wasn't faking it, no?
对
That's right.
你把她的死怪罪到了他的身上  上校 你今天喝酒了么?
And you blame him for her death. Have you been drinking today, Colonel?
喝了一杯 好久没喝了
I had a drink. I haven't been drinking.
我猜你从前喜欢和艾伦在一起喝酒吧
You used to like to drink with Ellen, I imagine.
你们听到了吗?
Do you hear that?
他们正在这里放音乐吗?
They're playing music in here now?
他在胡扯些什么?
What the hell is he talking about?
盖尤斯・波塔尔并没有下令处决你的夫人
LAMPKIN: Gaius Baltar didn't order the death of your wife.
上校  此事另有其人吧
Colonel, that was somebody else.
对吗  上校?
Who was it, Colonel?
谁害死了艾伦?
Who killed Ellen?
说吧  上校  大家都在等着
Come on, Colonel, we're waiting.
告诉我们吧
Tell us.
谁?  是谁害死了艾伦?
Who was it? Who killed Ellen?
我
I did!
是我
I did.
是我干的
她把情报泄露给了赛昂人
She was giving information to the Cylons.
许多好人为此牺牲
A lot of good men died.
她是我的太太  应该由我负责
She was my wife. It was my responsibility.
她这么做是为了我  这是她说的
She did it for me. That's what she said.
为了让我免受牢狱之灾  再受皮肉之苦
To save me from going back to prison so they could tear more pieces off me.
所以我杀了她
So I killed her.
这一切全因为那边那个东西
All because of that thing over there.
全因为他娘的盖尤斯・波塔尔
All because Gaius frakking Baltar
没胆量与赛昂人抗争
didn't have the guts to stand up to the Cylons.
因为他把我们的命运交付给了赛昂人
Because he handed our fates over to the Cylons,
我只好杀死了我的艾伦
I had to kill my Ellen.
即是盖尤斯・波塔尔 促使你杀害了你的夫人
So, Gaius Baltar made you kill your wife.
这也是你恨他的原因
That's why you hate him.
因此只要能置他于死地  你什么都会说
And that's why you'd say anything to see him die.
你算说对了
You're gods-damn right I would.
让我做什么
I would do anything,
说什么都行
say anything,
只要能看到那厮惨死
to see that man die a painful death.
没有问题了
No further questions.
把那音乐关了好吗?
Will someone turn off that music?
今天早些时候  示威者在…
MAN: Earlier today, eight protestors were arrested on...
你听到我在说什么吗?
Okay, are you hearing anything I'm saying?
我的天
My Gods.
海军陆战队被部署在舰…
A contingency of Colonial Marines were deployed to the ship.
要点什么?      我不知道要什么好
What can I get you? I don't know what I want.
你看着办吧 你是酒保
You figure it out. You're the bartender.
好 让你意想不到
Okay. Tell you what. I'll surprise you.
好 真不容易     谢谢
SAM: Yes, finally! SEELIX: Thank you!
我这个教练还不赖吧?
About time. I'm not a bad coach, huh?
再来一次         好
One more time. Yeah.
那天晚上我在学校批改作业  然后他们又来了
I was grading papers in the schoolhouse at night and they came again.
庆幸地是孩子们都已经走了 那时是天黑之后
Fortunately, the children were gone. It was after dark.
他们那晚带走了大约200名我们的同胞
They took close to 200 of our people that night,
这是波塔尔直接下令的
under Baltar's direct orders.
而事后证明 我们所有人的名字
As it turned out, all of our names were on a death list
都在波塔尔博士签署的死刑名单上
signed by Dr. Baltar.
让我们把这件事弄清楚
Let us be crystal clear on this fact.
你是说被告盖尤斯・波塔尔...
You are saying that the defendant, Gaius Baltar,
下令处决你和其他200名民众?
ordered your execution and the execution of 200 other people?
是的  正是  我就是这个意思
Yes, indeed. That's exactly what I'm saying.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我们必须找到任何能让他证言站不住脚的东西
BALTAR: We need to find something, anything, that can discredit her testimony.
她是个狂热者  对吧?  我不知道这一条是否有用
She's a fanatic, right? I don't know if that's gonna help.
你好安静
You're awfully quiet.
我在听你们说
I was just listening.
问题在于我是个高明的骗子  而你不是
You see, your problem is, is that I'm a really good liar and you're not.
说说吧
So let's have it.
说什么?
Have what?
我的天  他说对了 你确实知道一些事
My Gods, he's right. You do know something.
你知道一些事  却不肯说
You know something and you're not saying.
是不是真的都不知道 我已经有兴趣了
It's probably not even true. I like it already.
这是私事 我都怀疑她是否会对我说
It's a personal matter. I doubt she'd ever say anything in front of me.
她?  这是与劳拉・罗丝琳有关的事?
She! She! This is about Laura Roslin.
你却不…  告诉我  说啊      闭嘴
And you're not... Tell me, tell me! Shut up!
到现在为止挺自在啊?
Enjoying yourself so far? Hmm?
追随老头子
Having a good time sticking it to the old man,
来为世上最可恶的人辩护?
defending the most hated person in the universe?
这不是我同意干这份差事的原因
That's not why I agreed to do this.
对 你决定为真相与事实而抗争
No! You just decided to stand up for truth and justice
还有刻在法庭大门上的那些美好事物
and all those other lovely things we inscribe upon courtroom doors.
对
Yeah.
我就是在这么做 因为我相信这套法律体制
That's exactly what I'm doing. Because I believe in the system.
真的相信 我甚至相信…
I really believe... I even believe
我们这位下流胚的委托人应该得到公正的审判
that our lowlife pond scum of a client actually deserves a fair trial.
这里的法制要求你知无不言
The system requires that you tell what you know,
也就只给你留下两个不爽的选择
which leaves you with one of two uncomfortable options.
第一个选择  分享信息  这样做
First, share the information and in so doing uphold
你可以坚持你所看重的每条原则  或是第二个选择
the very principles that you claim to hold so dear, or second,
闭口不言
keep them to yourself,
彻底证明… 你来这里的唯一目的就是…
and prove, once and for all, your only purpose here
让你父亲颜面扫地
is to jab your father in the eye
让整套司法体制成为笑谈
and make a mockery of the entire justice system.
说得好 非常好 但我清楚我来这里的原因
That's very nice. Very, very nice. But I know why I'm here.
我用不着向你或别人证明
I don't need to prove it to you or to anyone else.
你错了
You're wrong.
你要向你自己证明 不然当你离开那法庭的时候
You need to prove it to yourself, or you leave that courtroom out there
就会想到你隐瞒的秘密可以挽救那个人悲惨的生活
knowing you kept a secret that could've saved that man's miserable life.
除非我看错了你
Now, unless I greatly misjudged your character,
否则李・亚当玛可不希望因这件事受到良心的谴责
that's not something that Lee Adama wishes on his conscience.
是什么事  少校?
So what'll it be, Major?
你是想隔岸观火?
Sit on the sidelines mouthing pieties?
还是想参与这场审判
Or are you gonna get in this trial,
提供给我们一些有用的情报?
give us something we can use?
好了  我们能行
Here we go! We made it!
来吧
Here we go, come on!
来吧  好了
Come on. There we go!
来吧
Here we go.
给我酒   你已经喝得够多了
Give me that. You had enough of that already.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
别担心
Don't worry.
今天有些好消息
Got some good news today.
我们找到泰里恩船上的辐射信号了
We found the radiation signature on the tylium ship,
正如那个赛昂犯人所说的一样
just like the Cylon prisoner said we would.
好极了
Good.
很好
That's great.
此时正在修理它
Being repaired as we speak.
盖塔先生...
Mr. Gaeta
估计舰队离那座星云还有九次跳跃距离
estimates the fleet's nine jumps away from the nebula.
考虑到修理泰里恩船所需的时间
Considering how long it's gonna take to fix the tylium ship,
再有三天的时间
we're out maybe three days.
三天后...
Three days out
就可以找到
from the next clue
通往地球的下一条线索
on the road to Earth.
我闻不到她的气味
I can't smell her.
我闻不到她的气味了  比尔
I can't smell her anymore, Bill.
我留着她的衣物
I kept her clothes,
可她的气味已经消失了
but her smell is gone now.
我得走了  少  真的累了
I gotta go, Saul. I'm really tired.
在法庭上发生的事 真不好意思
I'm sorry about all that in court.
没什么不好意思的
There's nothing to be sorry about.
我让你难堪了 让你很没面子
I embarrassed you. Made you look bad.
你是我的老友  少
You're my oldest friend, Saul.
你不会让我难堪的
You never embarrass me.
休息一下
Get some rest.
前任空军队长可以给上将一个极端的建议吗?
Can the former CAG make a radical suggestion to the Admiral?
我们不修理泰里恩船怎么样?
What if we don't fix the tylium ship?
已经开始修理了
Repairs have already started.
这我知道  不过听我把话说完
I realize that, but hear me out.
我们离那座星云太近 不能仅寄希望于解决问题后
We're too close to the nebula to simply fix the problem
赛昂人就不会找到我们 所以如果我们不去修理它
and hope the Cylons can't guess where we're going. So, if we don't fix it,
取而代之  我们改变该船的航线
if instead we send the ship off on a new course,
然后派几架猛禽机充当护卫 让他们在与舰队会合之前
with a couple of Raptors riding shotgun, let them make a few jumps
跳跃几次 这样也许就能摆脱赛昂人了
before rejoining the fleet, it might throw the Cylons off.
好主意
It's a good idea.
我考虑一下 还有什么事么?
I'll take it into consideration. Is there anything else?
总统的情况怎么样?
How's the President?
什么?
What?
她的身体还好么?
Is she okay?
她昨天在法庭上看起来有些不知所措
She looked a little rattled in court yesterday.
我们不能在法庭外谈论有关这次审判的事
We can't talk about the trial outside of court.
这你是知道的  应该知道
You know that, or you should.
我知道
I know.
我没有问…
I wasn't asking about...
在你对泰做出了那件事后
After what you did to Tigh,
我最不信任的人就是你
you're the last person I would consider to confide in.
我?
Me?
我没对泰做什么
I didn't do anything to Tigh.
他本来就醉了 不是我的错
He was drunk. It's really not my fault.
你把艾伦的事告诉了拉姆金
You told Lampkin about Ellen.
我都不知道有关艾伦的事
I didn't even know about Ellen.
省省吧
Yeah, right.
你是说我是骗子?
You calling me a liar?
你是骗子加懦夫
I'm calling you a liar and a coward.
一个没胆量
One who doesn't have the guts
去和别人单挑的人
to go after a man himself.
相反 你却把刀递给了一个陌生人
Instead, you hand the shift to a stranger,
让他在泰的背后捅上一刀
and let him stab Tigh in the back.
为了什么?
And for what?
就为了那个卖主求荣的废物 盖尤斯・波塔尔
That traitorous piece of garbage Gaius Baltar.
他就不配得到审判
He doesn't even deserve a trial.
你说完了吗?
Are you done?
完了
Yes.
那我也是
Then so am I.
我不会为一个质疑我的诚信的人效力
I will not serve under a man who questions my integrity.
我也不会让一个没有这种品质的人做我的部下
And I won't have an officer under my command who doesn't have any.
法庭上见  上将
I'll see you in court, Admiral.
让我来吧
Let me do this.
什么?
What?
你确定么  少校?
Are you sure, Major?
现在是布衣了 是的  我确定  应该由我来
It's mister now. And yeah, I'm sure. It should be me.
你不是真的要让我的护卫…
You're not seriously gonna let my security guard...
我们在等你  拉姆金先生
We're waiting, Mr. Lampkin.
如果法庭赏面 我的同事亚当玛先生将讯问证人
If it please the court, my associate, Mr. Adama, will question the witness.
他的同事
His associate.
辩方可以开始了
The defense may proceed.
谢谢
Thank you.
总统阁下 您能活到今天 难道不是盖尤斯・波塔尔的功劳吗?
Madam President, aren't you alive today because of Gaius Baltar?
我能活到今天 是因为起义军竭力阻止死刑的发生
I'm alive today because the insurgents managed to stop the execution.
他们从赛昂行刑队的手底下把您救了出来
Well, they saved you from a Cylon firing squad,
不过 难道不是波塔尔在您患上癌症后救您一命吗?
but wasn't it Baltar who saved your life when you were dying from cancer?
有何相干?
Relevance?
法官大人
Your Honors...
敌对证人  法官大人
Hostile witness, Your Honors.
如果法庭可以给我们三分薄面
If the court would grant us just a little latitude.
我们同意
We'll allow it.
谢谢
Thank you. Um...
盖尤斯・波塔尔 是否在您身患癌症的时候挽救了你?
Did Gaius Baltar save your life when you were dying from cancer?
波塔尔博士的科学知识确实挽救了我的生命
Doctor Baltar's scientific knowledge did save my life, indeed.
您能否详述一下?  他那时如何挽救了您的生命?
Can you be more specific? How did he save your life on that occasion?
他为我注射了取自一名半赛昂半人类的婴儿的血液
He injected me with the blood of a half-Cylon, half-human baby.
然后您的癌症就消失了?
And your cancer vanished?
完全消失了
Completely.
在您生病期间 您使用了何种药物?
During your illness, what sort of medication were you on?
那时我吃了很多药
You know, I was taking a lot of medications at the time
无法记住它们所有的名字
and I don't remember all their names.
您是否曾服用过 一种名为卡马拉汁的药品?
Did you take something called chamalla extract?
嗯
Hmm.
是的
Yes.
服用卡马拉的其中一项副作用...
Isnt it true that one of the
side effects of taking chamalla
是可能产生幻觉  这是否是真的?
is a propensity to experience hallucinations?
是的 这是卡马拉其中一项可能的副作用
Yes. That is one of the possible side effects of chamalla.
您所描述的...
And isn't it also true
从诸神那里得来的讯息...
that the visions that you once described as messages
是否可以看作其实是
from the Gods were actually the result
在服用卡马拉后药物反应的结果?
of a pharmacological reaction from taking chamalla?
卡马拉确实使我看到
The chamalla did enable me to see certain things
在经文上预言过的某些事物
that were foretold by the scriptures,
可以帮助这支舰队找到通往地球之路的讯息
things that will help this fleet find its way to Earth.
这你应该最清楚不过了  少校      法官大人
You, of all people, should know that, Major. Your Honors.
亚当玛先生 你的用意何在?
Mr. Adama, where are you going with this?
最后一个问题 法官大人
Just one more question, Your Honor.
求你别这么做 求你
Please, don't do this. Please.
总统阁下 您此时此刻是否服用了卡马拉?
Madam President, are you taking chamalla at this time?
"阿波罗上尉" 这个称谓你还记得么?
Captain Apollo, you remember that?
一直以来  我认为这是一个响铛铛的名字
I always thought it had such a nice ring to it.
我现在真为你感到惋惜
I am so, so sorry for you now.
卡马拉  总统阁下
Chamalla, Madam President.
也许被溶解在您的茶中来掩盖你的痛苦
Perhaps dissolved in your tea to mask the bitterness.
别回答  我现在就终止这场审判
Don't answer. I'm putting a stop to this, right now.
法官大人 如果她服用了此药
Your Honors, if she is on drugs,
她作为证人的可信度理应受到质疑
it goes to her credibility as a witness.
证人可以退庭了
Witness is dismissed.
法官大人  我必须强烈反对
Your Honors, I have to strongly object.
他显然试图在掩盖一些事情
He's obviously trying to cover something up, here.
你们再多说一个字  都会因蔑视法庭而被拘禁
One more word from you, and you'll both be held for contempt.
上将!  我想听证人…
Admiral! I'd like to hear the witness
回答问题   我也是
answer the question. As would I.
总统阁下 您是否又服用了卡马拉?
Madam President, are you taking chamalla again?
是的  服用了
Yes, I am.
没有问题了
No further questions.
亚当玛先生 难道你不问我为什么吗?
Mr. Adama, aren't you going to ask me why?
什么?  我为什么又再次服用卡马拉?
I'm sorry? Why am I taking chamalla again?
这并没有很大关系
It's not strictly relevant.
也许与你没什么相干 但却和我有关系
Well, perhaps it's not relevant to you, but it's relevant to me.
继续 问我为什么?
Go ahead. Ask me why.
要有始有终
Finish what you started.
您为什么又再次服用卡马拉 总统阁下?
Why are you talking the chamalla again, Madam President?
我再次服用卡马拉是因为我的癌症复发了
I am taking chamalla again because my cancer has returned.
她出现幻觉这一事实
You know, the fact that she's having hallucinations
与为波塔尔的辩护有联系
is relevant to Baltar's defense.
这就是法制的运作方式  小杜
That's the way the system works, Dee.
被告有权就证人的可信度提出异议
The accused has a right to challenge the credibility of witnesses against him.
事实就是如此
That's just the way it is.
法制已经失效了  李
The system is broken, Lee.
法制选举了那个男人当总统
The system elected that man to be president
法制还要让他逍遥法外
and the system is trying to let him walk.
这样的制度不值得我们去捍卫
That is not a system that deserves to be defended.
应该废除  应该重建
It deserves to be taken apart and put back together again.
我希望...
You know, I wish...
我希望我能够让你明白
I wish I could make you understand.
我明白  李
I do understand, Lee.
所以我才要离开的
That's why I'm leaving.
你不明白
Well, you don't.
你他妈的不明白
You frakking don't.
总统阁下 您对自己身患癌症所知多久了?
Madam President, how long have you known about the cancer?
大约一周的时间
About a week.
病情如何?
And how advanced is the disease?
您还会从半赛昂人那里输血吗?
Will you be getting any more transfusions from the half-Cylon donor?
我现在不想过多谈及像这样的细节
You know, this is the kind of detail I'm not going to go into now.
我们正在研究对策  制定好计划后我会通知你
You know, we're looking at a game plan. I'll let you know when we have one.
治病对您作为总统来说有多少影响?
Well, how the treatment for your illness impact your duties as president?
目前来说 一点也没有
So far, it hasn't at all.
您当前正在服用卡马拉汁么?
Are you currently taking chamalla extract?
别回答这个问题
Don't answer that.
您出现幻觉的间隔有多久?
How often do you hallucinate?
好了 胡说八道够了没有
All right, enough of this crap.
到此为止 托莉
We're done here. Tory.
你们这些秃鹰可以去找其他死尸了
You vultures can go pick over another carcass.
托莉 过来
Tory! Come here.
我们里面见  谢谢
I'll see you inside. Thank you.
不好意思 最近舰队里的温度比较高
I'm sorry. Temperatures are running a little high in the fleet these days.
到谁了?
Who's next?
克伦
Karen?
总统阁下 您还要活多久?
Madam President, how long do you have to live?
您还要活多久  克伦?
How long do you have to live, Karen?
您处理得很好
You handled that well.
你却没做好
You didn't.
用找其他死尸和我做对比?
"Picked over another carcass," as opposed to mine?
这话被媒体听到可有的瞧了
That's gonna look good in the press.
我不知道为什么自己会那么说
I don't even know why I said that. I...
你这是怎么了?
What is up with you?
几天来 你都无法正常工作  心神不宁  疲惫不堪
You've been off your game for days. You're distracted, you're exhausted.
坦率地讲 你简直让人讨厌
You're just, you know, frankly, you're plain obnoxious.
我近来睡眠不好
I just haven't been sleeping very well.
你要马上调整过来  把精力放在工作上
You need to pull it together and focus on your job, fast,
否则我照样能找到
or I can find someone
每周梳一次头发的人来应付媒体
who can handle the press, as well as pull a comb through their hair once a week
中尉   早安  副长
Lieutenant. Good morning, XO.
早安
Good morning.
暂时代班而已 上校会…
It's just temporary. The Colonel will...
振作起来的
Pull it together.
说得对
Right.
我们利用泰里恩船作为诱饵...
So, we're using the tylium ship as a decoy
把赛昂人吸引到了几乎与我们方向相反的这条航线上
to lead the Cylons along this course, here, almost directly opposite to ours.
当他们抵达这一点的时候 他们就会重新校准超光速引擎
When they reach this point here, they'll recalibrate the FTL,
开始往回跳跃
and start jumping back to rendezvous with Galactica
并将与全体舰队在爱奥尼亚星云这里相遇
and the rest of the fleet, here, at the lonian Nebula.
发现任何赛昂人追踪他们的迹象了吗?
Any indications the Cylons are following them?
还没有 他们似乎也停止追踪我们了
Nothing yet. And it would appear they've stopped following us as well.
自从泰里恩船脱离舰队以后
Our trailing Raptor has yet to pick up any sign of pursuit
我们的猛禽机没发现任何跟踪迹象
since the tylium ship left the fleet.
还有多少次跳跃 我们才能到达那座星云?
How many jumps until we reached the nebula?
呃
Uh...
难以置信 只需最后三次了
It's hard to believe, we're down to the last three.
好
Good.
还有什么事吗  长官?
Is there anything else, sir?
没有  我只是…
No, no. I was just...
只是想起在卡布里卡上...
Just remembering back on Caprica
当要变天的时候 你就能…
when the weather was about to change. You'd...
在空气中闻到这股味道
You'd get this smell in the air.
这时可能是烈日当空 万里无云
I mean, the sun could be out, not a cloud in the sky,
可你还是能闻到这股味道 并且知道…
but you'd pick up this smell and you knew that
有什么事情要发生了
something was just over the horizon.
要变天了  菲里克斯  我们要做好准备
Weather's changing, Felix. We need to be ready for it.
风暴即将来临了
There's a storm coming.
在船里
It's in the ship.
在他娘的船里
It's in the frakking ship!